A Guide to the Cary Reich papers FA1275
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Oral History Audio, circa 1980s (Bulk: 1982); 2
  - Q-R, 2.7
    - Roberts, Laurance, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9706)
      Interview. Roberts was Tod Rockefeller's cousin and a curator (1934-1946) and director (1938-1946) at the Brooklyn Museum. Under his leadership, the Brooklyn Museum produced numerous exhibitions and programs concerning Latin America, with extensive participation in the work of Nelson Rockefeller and the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs, under whose auspices the museum produced and circulated traveling exhibitions. Roberts was also involved in the founding of the New York State Council on the Arts in 1960-1961. Roberts interview ends at 30 minutes, 18 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with George Dudley until end. Dudley was an architect and gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Dudley worked alongside Wallace Harrison in designing and building the United Nations, Rockefeller Center, Lincoln Center, and the Empire State Plaza in Albany.
    - Rockefeller, David, circa1980s; Sound, 289 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9707)
      Interview. David Rockefeller was Nelson Rockefeller's brother. Rockefeller interview ends at 184 minutes. Tape then contains partial interview with George Dudley until 220 minutes, 58 seconds. Dudley was an architect and gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Dudley worked alongside Wallace Harrison in designing and building the United Nations, Rockefeller Center, Lincoln Center, and the Empire State Plaza in Albany. Tape then continues with David Rockefeller interview until end.
    - Rockefeller, Margaretta (Happy) - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 321 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9708A)
      Interview. Happy Fitler Rockfeller married Nelson Rockefeller in 1963.
    - Rockefeller, Margaretta (Happy) - Part 2, circa 1980s; Sound, 339 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9708B)
      Interview. Happy Fitler Rockfeller married Nelson Rockefeller in 1963. Rockefeller interview ends at 118 minutes, 51 seconds.
    - Rockefeller, Margaretta (Happy) - Part 3, circa 1980s; Sound, 124 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9708C)
    - Rockefeller, Jay, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9709)
      Interview with son of John D. Rockefeller 3rd; nephew of Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Rockefeller, Laurance, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9712)
      Interview. Younger brother of Nelson Rockefeller and one of his closest personal advisors.
    - 1. Rockefeller, Nelson on The Phil Donahue Show; 2. Adirondack Bill Signing Ceremony, 1. 1978; 2. 1973 May 22; Sound, 73 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9714)
      Tape begins with audio from Nelson Rockefeller's appearance on The Phil Donahue Show (Show number 11187) until 47 minutes, 16 seconds. Tape then contains audio from the Adirondack Bill Signing Ceremony on May 22, 1973 until 67 minutes. Tape is blank for the final six minutes. Rockefeller was Vice President of the United States, 1974-1977, Governor of New York, 1959-1973, Under Secretary of Health, Education and Welfare, 1953-1954, and Assistant Secretary of State for American Republic Affairs, 1944-1945. He also served as trustee, treasurer, and president of the Museum of Modern Art and founded the Rockefeller Brothers Fund in 1940 with his four brothers.
    - Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9711)
      Interview. Nelson Rockefeller, Jr. is the son of Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Rockefeller, Rodman, circa1980s; Sound, 301 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9715)
      Interview. Rodman Rockefeller was the son of Nelson Rockefeller. He was vice president of the International Basic Economy Corporation, 1968 to 1972, and its chief executive, 1972 to 1980. Rockefeller interivew ends at 25 minutes, 42 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Alton Marshall until 47 minutes. Marshall was Governor Nelson Rockefeller's chief aide, 1965-1971, and later became president of Rockefeller Center. Tape then continues with Rodman Rockefeller interview until 278 minutes, 19 seconds. Tape then contains another partial interview with Marshall until end.
    - Rogalin, Wilma, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9716)
      Interview. Rogalin was vice chairman of the New York State Republican Committee and president of its women's federation.
    - Romney, George, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9718)
      Interview. Romney was Governor of Michigan, 1963-1969, and Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, 1969-1973.
    - Ronan, William, circa1980s; Sound, 290 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9719)
      Interview. Ronan was a long-time aide and advisor to Nelson Rockefeller and a senior advisor to the Rockefeller family. He designed and served as the first chairman of the New York City Metropolitan Transportation Authority, 1968-1974. He then served as chairman of the Port Authority of New Yokr and New Jersey, 1974-1977.
    - Rosenbaum, Richard, circa1980s; Sound, 72 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9720)
      Interview. Rosenbaum was Monroe County Republican chairman, 1968-1970, a New York State Supreme Court justice, 1970-1972, and New York Republican State Committee chairman, 1973-1977.
    - Rosenberg, Anna, 1983 September 22; Sound, 53 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9721)
      Interview. Rosenberg was a friend and public relations advisor to Nelson Rockefeller. She served in President Franklin Delano Roosevelt's administration and advocated for Rockefeller to Roosevelt, leading to his appointment as Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs.
    - Rosenberg, Tom, circa1980s; Sound, 81 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9722)
      Interview. Rosenberger was Anna Rosenberg's son. Rosenbeg interivew ends at 54 minutes, 20 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with John Byron until end. Byron was director of construction of the South Mall for the State Office of General Services, an agency Governor Nelson Rockefeller created to oversee the project.
    - Rothberg, circa1980s; Sound, 39 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9723)
      Interview. Tape contains two separate interviews with individuals about investment banking and are not connected to Reich's Nelson Rockefeller biography.
    - Ruebhausen, Oscar, circa1980s; Sound, 308 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9724)
      Interview. Ruebhausen was a friend and advisor to Nelson Rockefeller. Under Governor Rockefeller, Ruebhausen served in a number of capacities, including as chairman of the Special Task Force on Protection from Radioactive Fallout, as Special Adviser on Atomic Energy, and as chairman of a panel on insurance holding companies.
    - Ruggieri, Bernard, circa1980s; Sound, 57 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9725)
      Interview. Ruggieri was head of the government relations department at the firm Shea and Gould, representing the legislative and executive branches of New York State and New York City. He was also elected head of the New York City Democratic Party in 1972.
    - Rumsfeld, Donald - Interview 1, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9726A)
      Interview. Rumsfeld was President Gerald Ford's White House Chief of Staff, 1974-1975, when Nelson Rockefeller was Vice President. Rumsfeld interview ends at 77 minutes, 39 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with J. Lawrence Murray until end. Murray worked for New York politician Frank Moore in various capacities during the 1950s and 1960s and served as acting chief administrative officer of the State University of New York, 1963-1964.
    - Rumsfeld, Donald - Interview 2, 1982 April 13; Sound, 18 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9726B)
      Interview. Rumsfeld was President Gerald Ford's White House Chief of Staff, 1974-1975, when Nelson Rockefeller was Vice President.
    - Rusher, Bill - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9727A)
      Interview. Rusher was publisher of National Review magazine and helped to found the Conservative Party of New York State in 1961 and the American Conservative Union in 1964. He worked on United States Senator Barry Goldwater's 1964 presidential campaign in which Goldwater won the Republican nomination.
    - Rusher, Bill - Part 2, circa 1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9727B)
    - Ryan, Jr., Andrew, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9728)
      Interview. Ryan was a New York State Assemblyman from the 110th district, 1968-1985. He opposed the creation of the Adirondack Park Agency.
  - S-T, 2.8
    - Scelsi, Michael, circa1980s; Sound, 188 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9730)
      Interview. Scelsi was executive director of the New York State Republican Committee, 1959-1965. Then after serving as Appointments Officer for two years, Governor Nelson Rockefeller appointed Scelsi to the New York State Civil Service Commission. Scelsi interview ends at 148 minutes, 2 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Schuler, Raymond - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 48 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9732)
      Interview. Schuler was instrumental in establishing the New York Department of Transportation and was appointed transportation commissioner in 1972 by Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Schuler was also the founder of The Business Council, New York's largest lobbying organization.
    - Schuler, Raymond - Part 2, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9733)
    - Schwenk, Edwin, circa1980s; Sound, 60 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9734)
      Interview. Schwenk was Republican Party chairman of Suffolk County, 1967-1977.
    - Scribner, Fred, circa1980s; Sound, 88 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9735)
      Interview. Scribner was a Dartmouth classmate of Nelson Rockefeller. He also served in the administration of President Dwight D. Eisenhower, rising to the position of Under Secretary of the United States Treasury, and was later general counsel to the Republican National Committee. Scribner interivew ends at 70 minutes, 5 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with General Theodore Parker until end. Parker was a general in the United States Army and served on Nelson Rockefeller's staff when Rockefeller was Special Assistant to the President for Psychological Warfare. Parker also served as New York State Commissioner of Transportation.
    - Sears Rockefeller, Barbara (Bobo), 1982 November 30; Sound, 46 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9470)
      Interview. Sears Rockefeller was an actress and the wife of Winthrop Rockefeller.
    - Sears, John, circa1980s; Sound, 73 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9736)
      Interview. Sears was a Republican pollitical strategist and served as advisor to Richard Nixon during the 1968 presidential campaign. He then served as Deputy Counsel to President Nixon, 1969-1970, and managed Ronald Reagan's 1976 presidential campaign.
    - Seidman, William, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9737)
      Interview. Seidman was executive director of Presdient Gerald Ford's Economic Policy Board and served as the president's assistant for economic affairs until 1977. Seidman interview ends at 46 minutes, 51 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Alan Miller until end. Miller was New York State Commissioner of Mental Hygiene, 1966-1975.
    - Shafer, Raymond, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9731)
      Interview. Shafer was Governor of Pennsylvania, 1967-1971, and gave the nominating speech for Governor Nelson Rockefeller at the 1968 Republican National Convention.
    - Shapiro, George, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9738)
      Interview. Shapiro was counsel to New York Governor Thomas Dewey.
    - Sharkey, Bill - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 298 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9739A)
      Interview. Sharkey was chief of revenue estimating for the New York State Department of Taxation and Finance. He moved on to work in the governor's office in 1959 where he worked on various tax and budgeting projects under Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Sharkey, Bill - Part 2, circa 1980s; Sound, 188 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9739B)
      Interview. Sharkey was chief of revenue estimating for the New York State Department of Taxation and Finance. He moved on to work in the governor's office in 1959 where he worked on various tax and budgeting projects under Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Sharkey interview ends at 155 minutes, 4 seconds. Tape then contains a partial phone call with an unidentified individual until 159 minutes, 30 second. Tape then contains partial interview with Tanya Melich unitl end. Melich was an aide to Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Shaw, Elizabeth, 22 November 1982; Sound, 138 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9740)
      Interview. Shaw was public relations director at the Museum of Modern Art.
    - Slater, Ilene, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9741)
      Interview. Slater was an executive assistant to Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Slote, Leslie, circa1980s; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9742)
      Interview. Slote was press secretary to Governor Nelson Rockefeller, 1966-1968. Slote interview ends at 32 minutes, 51 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with F. Clifton White until 47 minutes, 1 second. White was a political consultant and campaign manager for Republican Party and New York Conservative Party candidates. He was also a leader of the Draft Goldwater Committee, 1961-1964. Tapen then continues with Slote interview until end.
    - Spad, Carl, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9743)
      Interview. Spad was a campaign aide to Nelson Rockefeller and then Governor Rockefeller's Appointments Officer, 1959-1965. After resigning as Appointments Officer, Spad became New York Republican State Committee chairman, 1965-1967.
    - Spencer, Stuart, circa1980s; Sound, 62 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9744)
      Interview. Spencer was Governor Nelson Rockefeller's top political aide during the 1964 Republican presidential primaries.
    - St. Thomas, William - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 92 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9745)
      Interview. St. Thomas was Republican Party chairman of Saratoga County.
    - St. Thomas, William - Part 2, circa1980s; Sound, 45 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9746)
    - Stafford, Ron, circa1980s; Sound, 81 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9747)
      Interview. Stafford was a New York State senator, 1966-2002. His district included a significant portion of Adirondack Park. Senator Stafford was instrumental in bringing the Winter Olympic Games to Lake Placid in 1980, having been appointed chairman of the New York State 1980 Olympic Winter Games Commission in 1974.
    - Stark, Sheldon, circa1980s; Sound, 85 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9748)
      Interview. Stark was a classmate of Nelson Rockefeller at the Lincoln School and Dartmouth.
    - Stassen, Harold, circa1980s; Sound, 90 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9749)
      Interview. Stassen was a delegate at the conference that established the United Nations and was one of eight Americans who signed the United Nations Charter. He served in the adminstration of President Dwight D. Eisenhower for five years and sought the Republican nomination for President nine times between 1948 and 1988.
    - Steingut, Stanley, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9750)
      Interview. Steingut was a Democratic Assemblyman, 1952-1978, serving as Speaker of the Assembly, 1975-1978, and minority leader, 1969-1974. He was also Brooklyn Democratic chairman, 1962-1969.
    - Stephenson, Sir William, 1982 September 27; Sound, 40 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9751)
      Interview. Stephenson was British Prime Minister William Churchill's secret intelligence ambassdor to President Franklin D. Roosevelt. At the direction of Churchill, Stephenson established and ran the British Security Coordination, which was a covert organization operated out of Rockefeller Center with a purpose of investigating enemy activities, preventing sabotage against British interests in the Americas, and mobilizing pro-British opinion in the Americas. Stephenson supplied Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs Nelson Rockefeller with information on Nazi commercial activities in Latin America.
    - Stewart, Dick, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9752)
      Interview. From 1963-1967, Stewart was assistant, then first assistant counsel to Governor Nelson Rockefeller, and then became New York State Insurance Commissioner, 1967-1970.
    - Stone, Robert - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9753)
      Interview. Stone served as Executive Deputy Secretary of State and then Deputy Commissioner of General Services under Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Stone interview ends at 86 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Mike Scelsi until end. Scelsi was executive director of the New York State Republican Committee, 1959-1965. Then after serving as Appointments Officer for two years, Governor Nelson Rockefeller appointed Scelsi to the New York State Civil Service Commission.
    - Stone, Robert - Part 2, circa 1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9754)
      Interview. Stone served as Executive Deputy Secretary of State and then Deputy Commissioner of General Services under Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Stone interview ends at 40 minutes, 23 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Abby O'Neill until end. O'Neill was Nelson Rockefeller's niece.
    - Storrow, Linda Jamieson, circa1980s; Sound, 175 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9755)
      Interview. Storrow worked in Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs; spouse of Public Relations Director (Frank Jamieson) for Nelson Rockefeller's first campaign for the U.S. presidency in 1960. After Mr. Jameison died of cancer in 1960, Governor Rockefeller appointed Storrow the state's official greeter of foreign dignitaries to the city of New York.
    - Sutton, Percy, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9756)
      Interview. Sutton was a Democratic New York State Assemblyman, 1965-1966, and Manhattan borough president, 1966-1977.
    - Taylor, Arthur, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9757)
      Interview. Taylor formed the Sarabam Corporation with Nelson Rockefeller. Taylor interview ends at 32 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Joseph Crangle until end. Crangle was New York State Democratic chairman.
    - Teller, Edward - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9758A)
      Interview. Teller was a member of the Manhattan Project and a panelist on the International Security Objectives and Strategy sub-panel of the Special Studies project, which was conceived by Nelson Rockefeller and funded by the Rockefeller Brother's Fund.
    - Teller, Edward - Part 2, circa 1980s; Sound, 9 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9758B)
    - Terry, John, circa1980s; Sound, 170 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9759)
      Interview. Terry was assistant secretary to Governor Nelson Rockefeller, 1959-1961. Then he was a Republican New York State Assemblyman, 1963-1970, and a state congressman, 1971-1973.
    - Thaler, Manley, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9760)
      Interview. Thaler was Republican Party chairman of Tompkins County.
    - Thorne, Craig, circa1980s; Sound, 185 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9761)
      Interview. Thorne was a campaign aide and advance man for Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Tofany, Vincent, circa1980s; Sound, 114 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9762)
      Interview. Tofany was Republican Party chairman of Monroe County during the 1966 New York gubernatorial election.
    - Troy, Matthew, circa1980s; Sound, 88 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9763)
      Interview. Troy was a Democratic New York City councilman from Queens, 1964-1977, and the leader of the Queens Democratic Party, 1971-1974.
    - Trubin, John - Interview 1, circa1980s; Sound, 71 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9764A)
      Interview. Trubin was a campaign aide to Governor Nelson Rockefeller and negotiated deals for Rockefeller regarding the terms for televised debates.
    - Trubin, John - Interview 2, 1982 April 15; Sound, 33 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9764B)
  - U-Z, 2.9
    - Underhill, Jacob, circa1980s; Sound, 188 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9765)
      Interview. Underhill was a national affairs writer for Newsweek and then an assistant press secretary for Governor Nelson Rockefeller during the 1964 and 1968 presidential campaigns and the 1966 New York gubernatorial campaign.
    - Unidentified, circa1980s; Sound, 48 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9766)
      Interview. Tape contains two interviews with unidentified individuals from Batterymarch Financial Management regarding investing and trading. The first interview ends at 40 minutes, 10 seconds.
    - Unidentified, circa1980s; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9767)
      Interview. Tape contains two interivews with unidentified individuals from General Motors. First interivew ends at 11 minutes, 30 seconds.
    - Urstadt, Charles, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9768)
      Interview. Urstadt was deputy commissioner of the division of housing and community renewal, 1967-1969, and then commissioner, 1969-1973. He also helped found the Urban Development Corporation and was chairman of the Battery Park City Authority, 1968-1979.
    - Van Dyk, Ted and Gwirtzman, Milton, circa1980s; Sound, 51 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9770)
      Interview. Van Dyk is an author and was a senior assistant to Vice President Hubert Humphrey. Van Dyk interview ends at 27 minutes, 39 seconds. Tape then contains interview with Gwirtzman until end. Gwirtzman was an advisor and speech writer for John, Bobby, and Edward Kennedy.
    - Van Lare, Barry, circa1980s; Sound, 77 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9774)
      Interview. Van Lare was a consultant to states on welfare and related human services programs. He served as executive deputy commissioner and then acting commissioner of the New York Sate Department of Social Services.
    - Van Ness, Ed, circa1980s; Sound, 70 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9771)
      Interview. Van Ness worked on various health and human services issues in the Program Office and the New York State Health Department, including drug addiction, medicaid, and Governor Nelson Rockefeller's push for universal health insurance.
    - Vanden Heuvel, William, circa1980s; Sound, 91 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9772)